<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel xmlns:dsi="http://dsi.ucdavis.edu">
 <title>Data Science Related Events</title>
 <description>Events at UC Davis or nearby related to Data Science</description>
 <link>http://datascience.ucdavis.edu</link>
 <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
 <pubDate></pubDate>
 <ttl>1800</ttl>

<!--
<item id="">
<eventType></eventType>
<what></what>
<who></who>
<when>
</when>
<calendar></calendar>
<where><dsi:conf/><dsi:class/></where>
<description>
</description>
<expires>
</expires>
</item>
-->



<done>
<item id="RecomputingSS">
<when>Friday, May 19, 8.30am – 5pm</when>
<where>Multipurpose Room @ Student Community Center</where>
<title>Re-Computing Social Sciences</title>
<description>
Re-Computing Social Sciences: What Have We Learned After a Decade?"
Featuring 12 invited guest speakers from Stanford, UC Berkeley, UPenn, UCLA, Illinois, etc., and 12 UC Davis faculty
members. The workshop will be fast-paced and very interactive (the longest presentation will be 5 min long!) Please
register (free breakfast and lunch will be provided…)
</description>
</item>




<done>
<item id="danstandage">
<when>Friday, Oct. 7, 1pm - 2.30pm</when>
<where>360 Shields Library (DSI classroom)</where>
<title>Talk: Software tools and strategies or Scientific Software Development</title>
<description>
<p>
Speaker: Daniel Standage, Postdoc in the Lab for Data Intensive Biology
</p>
<p>
(Pizza will be provided.)
</p>
<p>
Although scientists in many fields are relying increasingly on
software for simulation, modeling, and data analysis, most scientists
have little or no formal training in software development and
engineering. Successfully managing a scientific software project
doesn't require you to become a professional software engineer, but
learning and using a handful of software development tools and
strategies can make a huge difference in the accuracy and usability of
the research software and in the efficiency of the software
development process.
</p>
<p>
In this presentation, we'll discuss tools (including version control,
code hosting services) and strategies (including project organization,
automated testing, pair programming, code review) that every coding
scientist should know about, as well as some considerations about
funding and credit that are unique to scientific software projects.
</p>
</description>
</item>









<item id="EntrepeneurDataSci">
<title>Data Science in the Wild</title>
<when>Mon, October 3rd, 1:00 pm – 3:00 pm</when>
<where>Auditorium 1005, Genome and Biomedical Sciences Facility (GBSF)</where>
<description>
<para>
Are you a postdoctoral researcher or PhD candidate looking to transition into a career in industry? Do you want a career
that leverages your quantitative experience in a fast-growing and in-demand field?
</para>
<para>
We invite you to attend an interactive workshop with Katie Amrine and Wafa Soofi, program directors and data scientists
at Insight Data Science in Silicon Valley. The workshop will focus on the topic: "What makes a good data science
project?"  We will also touch on general tips for preparing for a data science interview.
</para>
<para>
Insight is an intensive, seven-week postdoctoral training fellowship that bridges the gap between academia and a career
in data science. Based in Silicon Valley, Boston, and NYC, the program enables scientists to learn the industry specific
skills needed to work in the growing field of big data at leading technology companies.
</para>
<para>
This workshop is intended for anyone who is interested in data science; all backgrounds are welcome!  We have limited
available seats. Please <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/j0mdLgTpY23z1zwk1">RSVP ASAP</a>. 
</para>
<para>
Speakers: Katie Amrine, PhD and Wafa Soofi, PhD
</para>
<para>
Sponsored by The Davis Postdoc Entrepreneurship and Career group (DPEC)
</para>
</description>

</item>




<item id="STSFac">
<category>job</category>
<title>Tenure-track faculty position in "Data Studies"</title>
<description>
Tenure-track faculty position in an emerging Data Studies minor program and research with Data Scientists.
The position is expected to be 50% in Science &amp; Technology Studies (STS) and a new Data Science academic unit.
<a href="https://recruit.ucdavis.edu/apply/JPF01228">job description and application</a>
</description>
</item>

<item id="affiliates">
<when>Ongoing</when>
<title>Call for DSI postdoc/grad. student affiliates</title>
<description>
Apply to be a DSI affiliate to be part of a data science community.
Those selected will be able to use the DSI office space and interact
with others of a like mind across many disciplines.
Apply <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/18Tj5jMgueVm2eqfgxKh1AWxsNi3ZgoS-x7WribUzFj8/viewform">here</a>.
</description>
</item>
</done>





<item id="Fall16Courses">
<title><a href="Courses.html#Fall16">Fall16 Topics Courses</a></title>
<description>
Topics courses in Data-Science related topics that might be of interest.
</description>
</item>



<item id="iidata">
<title>iidata Data Science Convention</title>
<description>
iidata, a full-day experience dedicated to promoting Data Science and Statistics, features many exciting events
including tutorials/workshops, talks, competitions, research exhibition.
See <ulink url="http://www.iidata.net/workshops/"/>
</description>
<when>May 21st</when>
</item>


<item id="D3workgroup">
<title>D3 work group</title>
<when>Tuesday, June 14rd,  9am - 12</when>
<where>DSI space, Shields Library</where>
<description>
We are meeting to discuss and hack on visualization and D3-related projects.
</description>
</item>

<item id="D3materials">
<title>D3 workshop materials</title>
<description>
<ulink url="http://dsi.ucdavis.edu/D3materials">Web page</ulink>
and <ulink url="https://github.com/duncantl/D3materials">git repos</ulink>
</description>
</item>



<done>
<item id="RFP">
<when>Ongoing</when>
<title>Call for 1- or 2- quarter Projects</title>
<description>
The DSI team will work with selected groups on projects that would significantly benefit
from data science skills.
See <a href="DSICallForProjects-1.pdf">here for more information</a> about how to apply.
We will continue to accept proposals after April 1st.
</description>
</item>



<item id="AdvBegPython">
<title>Advanced Beginner Python</title>
<where>1043 Valley Hall, UC Davis Campus</where>
<when>April 4, 2016, 9 - 12.15</when>
<description>
<p>So you've written some Python code and it works! Now what?</p>
<p>
This half day workshop will explore "next steps" in Python
programming -
<ul>
<li> reusing code by placing it in importable modules;</li>
<li> code organization overall;</li>
<li>handling command line arguments with argparse;</li>
<li>simple testing strategies and tools, including code coverage;</li>
<li>using virtualenv to install isolated collections of software on
  shared machines;</li>
</ul>
Attendees should have some Python experience, but need not be experts.
</p>
</description>
</item>



<item id="beginGit">
<title>Beginner Git</title>
<description>
<p>
Description: Git and related systems are key for replicability when doing any kind of computational analysis. This
introductory workshop will cover creating a repository, recording and viewing changes to files, ignoring files, working
with GitHub online, resolving conflicts, open licenses, and where to host work.
</p><p>
This workshop will be taught remotely and broadcast to our classroom
via Google Hangouts on Air. We will have helpers in our local room to
facilitate the lesson. The lesson will also be streamed to YouTube and
saved there for viewing at a later time.
</p>
<p>
For more information, including VT information: http://dib-training.readthedocs.org/en/pub/2016-04-06-intro-git-br.html
</p><p>
Davis participants register here (only if planning to come to the classroom):
https://www.eventbrite.com/e/introductory-git-version-control-your-workflow-tickets-24030735577
</p>
</description>
<where>DSI classroom, 360 Shields Library</where>
<when>April 6, 2016, 9 - 12.15</when>
</item>




<item id="cmdlineGit">
<title>Ultra-Basic Introduction to the Command Line and Git</title>
<when>April 8, 9 - 12</when>
<description>
Basic skills using the Unix/Linux command line and the Git version control system are prerequisite to the application of
nearly all digital methods.  This workshop will offer a down and dirty, no holds barred introduction to both.  While
both technologies are rich and multi-faceted, this workshop does not, by design, aim towards comprehensiveness nor
complete mastery.   Rather, it is designed to introduce participants to a basic toolkit that will allow them to perform
most tasks regularly required of beginning developers.
</description>
</item>





<item id="hack4sac">
<title>Hack4Sac data competition</title>
<description>
<a href="http://hack4sac.saccounty.net/">Hack4Sac data competition details</a>
A 6 week event with multiple competitions for working with Sacramento's open data portal.
</description>
<when>Starts March 1</when>
</item>



<item id="Sphinx">
<title>Sphinx, Webhooks, and Bitbucket workshop</title>
<description>This workshop will cover using webhooks with Bitbucket to create Web sites that automatically update when
you make changes in a Bitbucket repository. Sphinx and reStructuredText will be used to build the underlying Web site.
This workshop will be taught remotely and broadcast to UC Davis via Google Hangouts. It will also be streaming on
YouTube.
Register at: 
<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sphinx-webhooks-and-bitbucket-half-day-workshop-tickets-20041061354">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/sphinx-webhooks-and-bitbucket-half-day-workshop-tickets-20041061354</a>
</description>
<when>February 29th, 2016, 9:15 am - 12:25pm</when>
<url>http://dib-training.readthedocs.org/en/pub/2016-02-29-sph-webh-bitb-lr.html</url>
</item>











<item id="titusAdvShell">
<title> Advanced Beginner Shell workshop, January 13</title>
<description>
Advanced Beginner Shell
<p>
Who: Titus Brown<br/>
When: January 13, 2016<br/>
Times: 9:15am-12:15pm<br/>
Where: Valley Hall, UC Davis campus. (Room TBD)
</p>
<p>
This half-day workshop will continue from the end of the Beginning Shell lesson
(see materials here: https://github.com/ngs-docs/2015-shell-genomics/blob/gh-pages/README.rst).
We will cover loops, if statements, scripting, and I/O redirection (&gt;, &lt;, etc.).
We will also talk a bit about how to put together shell scripts for job submission
on queuing systems (`qsub' etc.).
</p>
<p>
This workshop is open to everyone, including graduate students,
postdocs, staff, faculty, and community members. We have reserved
space for UC Davis VetMed affiliates; please contact the lead
instructor if you are affiliated with the SVM.  These spaces will
be released a week before the workshop.
</p>
<p>
More at:
<a  href="http://dib-training.readthedocs.org/en/pub/2016-01-13-adv-beg-shell.html">http://dib-training.readthedocs.org/en/pub/2016-01-13-adv-beg-shell.html</a>
</p>
</description>
</item>




<item id="SoftwareCredit">
<title>Crediting Software for Science: Scholarship beyond the research article</title>
<rsvp>events@geodynamics.org</rsvp>
<when>Monday, June 1, 11:30am - 1:30pm</when>
<where>Library Instruction Room (LIR), 205, Shields Library</where>
<description>
What do you do to promote software citation in your scientific community? <br/>
We invite you to come together with other investigators on campus spanning the rich diversity of campus research in addressing this question. The goal of this brown box lunch is to create a campus community of and start a conversation amongst research software developers to share practices and needs in the area of software citation.  The luncheon will open with a lightening round of introductions from all participants which we hope will invigorate both large and small group discussion over an informal lunch.
</description>

</item>




<ignore>
<old>
<item id="LLNLInterns">
<title><a href="http://careers-ext.llnl.gov/jobs/4421119-computation-student-intern--2">Computational internships at Lawrence Livermore National Lab</a></title>
<description>
<a href="http://careers-ext.llnl.gov/jobs/4421119-computation-student-intern--2">Computational internships at Lawrence Livermore National Lab</a>
There are openings for projects related to high-performance computing and / or data analysis.
The application should be turned in late Jan / Feb 2016 for the best chance of acceptance.
</description>
</item>
</old>
</ignore>


<!--
<item id="DSSG">
<title><a href="http://dssg.uchicago.edu">UC Chicago's Data Science for Social Good</a> summer program</title>
<description>
Applications for the Summer 2016 program are due Feb 1, 2016
</description>
</item>
-->



<item id="ISSLaunch">
<title>ISS 3-part Conference</title>
<description>
The Institute for Social Sciences is holding its inaugural conference
on three consecutive Fridays, starting 24th April.
</description>
<when>Each Friday 24th April, May 1 and 8.</when>
<url label="Web site">http://socialscience.ucdavis.edu/events/iss-conference</url>
</item>




<item id="MemeCentralAd">
<title>RA Position, Summer 2015</title>
<description>
<html>
Graduate Student Summer Research Opportunity
<p>
A graduate student researcher is being sought for 2 to 2.5 months during summer 2015 to work on a project titled, "Music-evoked remembering in the age of Big Data." The project is being supervised by Dr. Petr Janata (Psychology) in association with Drs. Duncan Temple Lang (Statistics), Raul Aranovich (Linguistics), and Arne Ekstrom (Psychology). 
</p>
<p>
<a href="http://socialscience.ucdavis.edu/research/music-evoked-remembering-in-the-age-of-big-data">Project Description</a>
</p>

<p>
The project combines psychology, neuroscience, linguistics, statistics, and computer science.  We are seeking a student who can contribute to the technical core of the project, which has social media, semantic web, and neuroimaging components. The successful candidate will have skills that cover some number of the following programming and query languages, protocols, and toolkits: Python, JavaScript,  R, MATLAB, RDF/RDFS/OWL, SPARQL, Prolog, nltk, TXM, and d3.  Experience working in the Amazon Web Services environment is desirable but not required.  Excellent programming and documentation practices are mandatory.
</p>
<p>
To apply, please submit a letter of interest to pjanata@ucdavis.edu that states why you are interested in this project and how it interfaces with your current or future research interests.  Enumerate your relevant skills.  Indicate your availability between the end of Spring Quarter 2015 and the start of Fall Quarter 2015.
</p>
<p>
All applications received by the end of the day, Friday, May 1, 2015, will be considered.
</p>
<p>
For more information, please contact Petr Janata (pjanata@ucdavis.edu)
</p>
</html>
</description>
</item>





<!--
<item id="STA101">
<title>Statistics/Data Science Course in Spring - STA242</title>
<description>
Data Science Computing topics. (R, computational efficiency, parallel computing, interfacing to C, 
shell filtering, Hadoop, statistical methods). Instructor: Duncan Temple Lang
</description>
<when>9 - 10.50, Tuesday &amp; Thursday, Spring Quarter</when>
</item>


<item id="STA101">
<title>New Statistics Course in Spring - STA101</title>
<description>
There is a new course being taught in Statistics this Spring Quarter, STA101
</description>
<when>Spring Quarter</when>
</item>
-->

<!-- 
<item id="Workday">
<title>Liang Huang, Data Scientist</title>
<description>What data science is all about at Workday.
<ulink url="https://www.facebook.com/events/932958976754124/"/></description>
<when>Tuesday, Mar 10, 2015, 7:00 pm - 8:30pm</when>
<where>Giedt Hall, Room 1006</where>
</item>




<item id="CSISPlantin">
<title>CSIS: Seminar Jan 27th</title>
<description>
More Data, More People, More Conflicts. The Power of Visualization Technologies in a Big Data Era.
<i>Jean-Christophe Plantin</i>,  Communication Studies Department, U Michigan</description>
<when>Tuesday January 27th from 4:10 - 5:30 PM </when>
<where>126 Voorhies</where>
</item>

<item id="PlantSciMa">
<title>Plant Sciences Seminar: Jan 28</title>
<description>From "Big Data" to biological pathways - gene networks and protein microarrays to understand plant signaling systems.
<i>Shisong Ma</i>, Dinesh-Kumar Lab, UCD.  </description>
<when>Wednesday, Jan. 28, 12:10 – 1:00</when>
<where>PES 3001</where>
</item>




<!--
 <item id="DataRights">
  <title>Data Rights &amp; Data Wrongs</title>
  <html><a href="Events.html#DataRights">Data Rights &amp; Data Wrongs!</a></html>
  <when>Wednesday, December 10, 2014</when>
  <url>https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-rights-data-wrongs-tickets-14079810091</url>
  <description>
   A workshop organized by Innovating Communication in Scholarship (ICIS), University of California, Davis.
  </description>
 </item>


 <item id="TownHall">
  <title>Data Science Town Hall Discussion</title>
  <description>
   We invite faculty, researchers, postdocs and grad students with any interest
   in Data Science on campus to participate in a discussion about what
   the Data Science Initiative can do to foster and promote an inter-disciplinary community
   and its activities.  We really want to hear your suggestions and priorities.
   This will be held in the Nelle Branch room on the 2nd floor of Shields Library.
   <a href="http://www.lib.ucdavis.edu/ul/about/locations/?map=shields-floor-2">map</a>
  </description>
  <when>January 13th,  12 - 1.15 (lunch provided)</when>
  <url davisOnly="true">https://docs.google.com/a/ucdavis.edu/forms/d/1L_3xzhcsawWX5D-H9NYYl2Xgx43UiWtY0BzljPOlF1c/viewform?usp=send_form</url>
  <where></where>
 </item>
-->

<!--
 <item id="OfficeHours">
 <title>Drop-in Office Hours</title>
  <description>
    Carl Stahmer (Director of Digital Scholarship) &amp;
    Duncan Temple Lang (Interim Director of the Data Science Initiative &amp; Professor, Dept. of Statistics)
  will hold drop-in consulting/office hours on all things  Digital  and Data Science (Statistics, Applied Computing, Visualization, Workflows, Reproducability, ...).
   Stop by or, better yet, <a href="mailto:datascience@ucdavis.edu">email us</a> ahead of time.
  </description>
  <when>Each Thursday, 10 - 11am</when>
  <where>Room 362a, Shields Library (follow signs for the old Inter Governmental Affairs space)</where>
  <period>January 22nd - March 19th</period>
 </item>
-->

<!--

 <item id="PythonMiniCourse">
  <title>Python for Data Analysis Mini-course</title>
  <description>
This mini-course is primarily intended for statistics students, but open to others as space permits.
We will meet twice a week for 4 weeks.
PhD graduate students Clark Fitzgerald and Nick Ulle will be the primary instructors,
with support from Profs. Duncan Temple Lang and Wolfgang Polonik.
This is sponsored jointly by the Statistics <a href="http://www.stat.ucdavis.edu/research/nsf-rtg/index.html"><b title="Research Training Grant">RTG</b></a> and
the Data Science Initiative.
  </description>
  <when>Tuesday &amp; Thursday,  2 - 3.30 </when>
  <where>Math Sciences Building, 1147</where>
  <period>Jan 13th - Feb 5th</period>
  <url>https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1oPzK1PwbyoonaSiPOAvHqwKe7uDOYoDP95TVw8GBppA/viewform?usp=send_form</url>
 </item>

 <item id="BrownBagSeminar">
  <title>Brown Bag Seminar</title>
  <when>Winter Quarter</when>
 </item>
-->
<!--
 <item id="Workshop">
  <title>Workshop</title>
  <when>Winter Quarter</when>
 </item>
-->
 
</channel>
</rss>
